<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>The Spicy Stew</title>
	<subtitle>Site feed.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://myurl.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://myurl.com/"/>
	<updated>2019-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
	<id>https://myurl.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Kenneth Johnson</name>
		<email>kennyaj123@gmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Welcome to The Spicy Stew</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-03T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome! I&#39;m DiggyJohnson, and I&#39;m excited to get going with this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why%3F&quot;&gt;Why? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#why%3F&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for a blog started out as a joke between a buddy and myself. But upon thinking more about it, we realized there really isn&#39;t much written OSRS content (and I needed to practice my webdev and cloud architectures skills anyways). While Youtube/Twitch is the primary medium for content creators, it has a huge amount of overhead. On the other hand, blogging is as easy as opening a text editor and getting my thoughts on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for a post in the near future enumerating some of the content ideas we have for The Spicy Stew, and as always please do not hesitate to reach out with your own feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Content Direction of The Spicy Stew</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/secondpost/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/secondpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the core goals of The Spicy Stew is to pursue a wide variety of content. While I&#39;m sure things will change in the future, I wanted to provide some sort of list of ideas to give some context to the direction of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;research-and-analysis&quot;&gt;Research and Analysis &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#research-and-analysis&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Stew&#39;s meat and potatoes. The wave of snowflake ironmen has opened the door on a huge amount of dead, forgotten and unused content. We want to dive into their world, and see if we can help out by doing some research. On the flipside, many of these accounts have uncovered dead content that may deserve another look by the general playerbase. Either way, we&#39;ll cover it in a blog post and somebody wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research and Analysis can really be anything related to the (non-social) components of OSRS. This is an extremely flexible area of focus, so expect the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;satire&quot;&gt;Satire &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#satire&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satire will spice the stew. Honestly, we&#39;re all really wasting our lives playing Runescape, so sometimes it may be worth pointing out the absurdity of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#community&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSRS community is...special. While we can&#39;t hope to cover everything that people find a way to care about, if we have a decent or unique take on something you can find it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a lot of spiciness here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;history-and-lore&quot;&gt;History and Lore &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#history-and-lore&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easy to forget just how huge Gielinor is. It turns out there&#39;s a lot of interesting stuff in the dialogues we all spacebar through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are these ruins here? Why is Elvarg so easy to kill? The list goes on; there&#39;s a lot to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could also include the history of the game. Remember when people bursted rock lobsters??? Runescape runs on nostalgia, so let&#39;s tap into some of the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list does not pretend to be exhaustive, nor can I make any promises about scheduled content at this point. I&#39;m just gonna wing it, and write what I feel like writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to contribute your own content, send me a message on Reddit and we&#39;ll get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Runescape Through Adulthood 1: Are Dating and OSRS Compatible?</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/runescape-through-adulthood01/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/runescape-through-adulthood01/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://myurl.com/img/buyinggf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buying girlfriend image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#introduction&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Runescape community is growing up. As such, many players must grapple with new factors that may inhibit the progress of their account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it may be uncommon, some players even find themselves in relationships - or at the very least are considering the possibility of pursuing a meaningful relationship. In this article, we set out to analyze whether a relationship with a real life person is worth the lost EHP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no question that most IRL relationships do negatively impact average EHP gain, so we will focus on whether the happiness output of a relationship outweighs the lost EHP. &lt;strong&gt;By the end of this farce, we do NOT expect to claim that all players should or should not pursue IRL relationships, but to illuminate the cases where relationships are more likely to be worth the lost EHP. We also want to provide a quantified value for converting relationships to lost EHP, and a framework for comparing whether increased happiness is worth the lost EHP.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will start simple in this first installment, and try to quantify the lost EHP of relationships. In the future, we will dive into the literature for a more nuanced understanding of the trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* &lt;em&gt;EHP -&amp;quot;Efficient Hours Played - is a standard metric used to compare xp gains across skills. Read more about it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://crystalmathlabs.com/tracker/faq.php&quot;&gt;https://crystalmathlabs.com/tracker/faq.php&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** &lt;em&gt;Citations for peer reviewed resources can always be found at the end of this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first started pondering these sorts of questions, I figured it made sense to use myself as an anecdotal guinea pig. The interview produced below occurred between me and my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This interview occurred before I had really formulated my key questions, so I will admit that the questions do not optimally address the goals of this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;section-0%3A-the-interview%3A&quot;&gt;Section 0: The Interview: &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#section-0%3A-the-interview%3A&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Context: this interview was conducted in our University&#39;s library while Hallie was very busy with an assignment. Perhaps I should have chosen a more clinical and deliberative setting. Despite this, I think this conversation serves as a useful jumping off points for the rest of the article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How many hours a day do you think we spend together that I would otherwise have to myself if we weren&#39;t together?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Maybe 3 hours a day, I don&#39;t know..?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Do you think my passion for Runescape is a good thing? Why or why not?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Uhhhh...neutral. &lt;em&gt;giggles uncomfortably&lt;/em&gt;. I wouldn&#39;t say its like a great thing, but it could be so much worse? Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: &amp;quot;Do you think Runescape makes me more attractive/hot. Why or why not?&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Definitely does not make you more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:  Would you be upset with me if I chose to not hang out with you to level up a skill?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: If that was the reason and it really made you happy, you do you. (&lt;em&gt;Authors note: there&#39;s no way this is true.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[HER] Q: What&#39;s this about?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ME] A: I&#39;m trying to come up with the average xp waste generated by a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q: ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;she leaves&lt;/em&gt; (comes back later tho)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while this was a fun way to procrastinate, there&#39;s obviously not a whole lot of value to extract from this conversation. We must dive deeper...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chapter-1%3A-the-ehp-cost-of-dating&quot;&gt;Chapter 1: The EHP Cost of Dating &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#chapter-1%3A-the-ehp-cost-of-dating&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you care at all about &lt;em&gt;the grind&lt;/em&gt;, you should constantly be thinking about how allocating time for in-real-life activities takes away from account progress. This is the same concept as considering purchasing decisions by their time-value - e.g. If you make $10/hr, is that $6 Chipotle burrito really worth 36 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I could not find any data in the literature for the average daily amount of &amp;quot;personal time&amp;quot; that are lost in relationships. As such, I polled a few of my friends to come up with a rough estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average lost daily personal time: 3 hrs/day (n=6 males; avg. age = 21 years). Lets put that time into meaningful perspective using EHP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that EHP assumes the most efficient method possible of leveling the skill with an alt for making money. As such, I provide a ballpark estimate for lost xp for the more casual player in the third column. Please do not eat my ass because my estimate of casual play is different than yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EHP Rates given for 1,000,000 xp in the relevant skill. That corresponds to level 73. You can find exact rates at &lt;a href=&quot;https://crystalmathlabs.com/tracker/suppliescalc.php&quot;&gt;https://crystalmathlabs.com/tracker/suppliescalc.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Skill&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;EHP Relationship Opportunity Cost (xp/day)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ballpark Estimate for the Filthy Casual (xp/day)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Attack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;190,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Strength&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;190,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Defense&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;950,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hitpoints&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ranged&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Prayer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5,400,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,800,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Magic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cooking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,470,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Woodcutting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;540,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fletching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,100,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fishing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;261,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Firemaking&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,000,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Crafting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;990,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Smithing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,124,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;540,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mining&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;270,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;135,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Herblore&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Agility&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Thieving&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;660,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slayer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Farming&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,050,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Runecrafting&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;375,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hunter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;603,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Construction&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,700,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,200,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZAM ZADDY! That&#39;s a lot of EHP!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to put that in perspective, if you used to play four hours a day in your personal time, and you lose three of those hours because you &amp;quot;found someone,&amp;quot; you should be constantly aware of the fact that you are hemorrhaging xp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using that example and my account as an example, I am 1043 efficient hours played away from maxing. I do not play efficiently or use alts, so let&#39;s call it 1500 hours. At 4 hrs/day, I would max in 375 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if I lose three of those hours, now I&#39;m 1500 days - or almost 5 years - away from my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is just an example and every case is different, but it serves a useful purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;chapter-1-conclusion&quot;&gt;Chapter 1 Conclusion &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#chapter-1-conclusion&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We just skimmed the surface in Chapter 1; there is much more rigorous content to come. The goal today was not to provide ground breaking information, but more to state the obvious and to provide the cognitive foundation needed to tackle the nuance of the issue later in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have a jumping off point to consider arguments like: &amp;quot;is jerking off and playing Runescape more efficient than pursuing a relationship and being 10% happier?&amp;quot; For that question - and many - stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
</feed>
