<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>The Spicy Stew</title>
	<subtitle>Site feed.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://myurl.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://myurl.com/"/>
	<updated>2019-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
	<id>https://myurl.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Kenneth Johnson</name>
		<email>kennyaj123@gmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Welcome to The Spicy Stew</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-03T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome! I&#39;m DiggyJohnson, and I&#39;m excited to get going with this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why%3F&quot;&gt;Why? &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#why%3F&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea for a blog started out as a joke between a buddy and myself. But upon thinking more about it, we realized there really isn&#39;t much written OSRS content (and I needed to practice my webdev and cloud architectures skills anyways). While Youtube/Twitch is the primary medium for content creators, it has a huge amount of overhead. On the other hand, blogging is as easy as opening a text editor and getting my thoughts on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for a post in the near future enumerating some of the content ideas we have for The Spicy Stew, and as always please do not hesitate to reach out with your own feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Content Direction of The Spicy Stew</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/secondpost/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/secondpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the core goals of The Spicy Stew is to pursue a wide variety of content. While I&#39;m sure things will change in the future, I wanted to provide some sort of list of ideas to give some context to the direction of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;research-and-analysis&quot;&gt;Research and Analysis &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#research-and-analysis&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Stew&#39;s meat and potatoes. The wave of snowflake ironmen has opened the door on a huge amount of dead, forgotten and unused content. We want to dive into their world, and see if we can help out by doing some research. On the flipside, many of these accounts have uncovered dead content that may deserve another look by the general playerbase. Either way, we&#39;ll cover it in a blog post and somebody wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research and Analysis can really be anything related to the (non-social) components of OSRS. This is an extremely flexible area of focus, so expect the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;satire&quot;&gt;Satire &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#satire&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Satire will spice the stew. Honestly, we&#39;re all really wasting our lives playing Runescape, so sometimes it may be worth pointing out the absurdity of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;community&quot;&gt;Community &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#community&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSRS community is...special. While we can&#39;t hope to cover everything that people find a way to care about, if we have a decent or unique take on something you can find it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a lot of spiciness here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;history-and-lore&quot;&gt;History and Lore &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#history-and-lore&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be easy to forget just how huge Gielinor is. It turns out there&#39;s a lot of interesting stuff in the dialogues we all spacebar through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are these ruins here? Why is Elvarg so easy to kill? The list goes on; there&#39;s a lot to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could also include the history of the game. Remember when people bursted rock lobsters??? Runescape runs on nostalgia, so let&#39;s tap into some of the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this list does not pretend to be exhaustive, nor can I make any promises about scheduled content at this point. I&#39;m just gonna wing it, and write what I feel like writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to contribute your own content, send me a message on Reddit and we&#39;ll get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Runescape Through Adulthood 1: Are Dating and OSRS Compatible?</title>
		<link href="https://myurl.com/posts/thirdpost/"/>
		<updated>2019-03-26T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://myurl.com/posts/thirdpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Organically grow the holistic world view of disruptive innovation via workplace diversity and empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// this is a command&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;myCommand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ins class=&quot;highlight-line highlight-line-add&quot;&gt;	&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; counter &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;del class=&quot;highlight-line highlight-line-remove&quot;&gt;	counter&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Test with a line break above this line.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;console&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&#39;Test&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring to the table win-win survival strategies to ensure proactive domination. At the end of the day, going forward, a new normal that has evolved from generation X is on the runway heading towards a streamlined cloud solution. User generated content in real-time will have multiple touchpoints for offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;section-header&quot;&gt;Section Header &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#section-header&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blah blah blah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capitalize on low hanging fruit to identify a ballpark value added activity to beta test. Override the digital divide with additional clickthroughs from DevOps. Nanotechnology immersion along the information highway will close the loop on focusing solely on the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
</feed>
